<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Problems on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/problems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Problems on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It is never too early to think about productivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/it-is-never-too-early-to-think-about-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/it-is-never-too-early-to-think-about-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Functional requirements are where business application users&amp;rsquo; needs are mostly expressed. The architect is in charge of the system&amp;rsquo;s non-functional elements, which include performance, flexibility, downtime, support requirements, etc. Simultaneously, initial testing of non-functional needs is sometimes completely assigned to the system maintenance team or delayed until a very late point in the development cycle.&#xA;This is a far more frequent error than it ought to be. It may be founded on a number of factors.It may seem futile to worry about the program&amp;rsquo;s speed and adaptability when it isn&amp;rsquo;t precisely fulfilling the necessary role yet. Both the test settings and the tests themselves are highly intricate. Due to low use intensity, early working versions of the system might not have been subjected to a realistic load.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Try not to break the schedule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/try-not-to-break-the-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/try-not-to-break-the-schedule/</guid>
      <description>Numerous factors can cause a software project to fail. Changing the work schedule mid-project without enough planning is one of the most frequent causes of project failure. These kinds of failures are preventable, but it will take a lot of work from many individuals. Adding resources or modifying the timeline to a project typically doesn&amp;rsquo;t cause any issues. When you have to work more in the same amount of time or reduce the timetable without lowering the workload, problems arise.&#xA;A very prevalent fallacy is that you can cut expenses or expedite product delivery by shortening the timeline. Usually, extra hours are worked or &amp;ldquo;less important tasks&amp;rdquo; (such modular testing) are given up for quicker product delivery or for better functionality without affecting delivery time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problems can be more than their reflection in the mirror</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/problems-can-be-more-than-their-reflection-in-the-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/problems-can-be-more-than-their-reflection-in-the-mirror/</guid>
      <description>I have several programming projects that I have been working on.They all ran into issues that proved to be more problematic than the development team had anticipated.This frequently happened in the following ways: while some team members identified these issues early on, the majority of employees rejected or disregarded any indications because they didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize their significance until it was too late.&#xA;There are several reasons why this occurs:&#xA;Issues that appear unimportant early in the project grow important when it is too late to address them.Although the tale of the welded frog is undoubtedly exaggerated, it well captures what goes wrong in many undertakings.&#xA;Some workers frequently run into opposition when other team members lack comparable expertise or experience.Even highly compensated seasoned consultants recruited expressly to avoid such issues rarely possess the guts, confidence, and perseverance needed to overcome this opposition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps your main problem is not technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</guid>
      <description>Somewhere right now, a different wage calculation project is failing miserably&amp;hellip; and most likely not by yourself.&#xA;What caused that to occur? because the developers opted for Ruby over Smalltalk or Java or Python? since you choose to utilize Postgres over Oracle? or because you preferred the Windows platform even if you should have chosen Linux? As you are aware, technology is frequently held responsible for project failures.&#xA;People normally establish projects, and it is up to these individuals to decide whether the project as a whole succeeds or fails. And once that is the case, we ought to consider our options for assisting them in being successful.&#xA;Per, you believe that there is a team member that is underperforming and impeding the project&amp;rsquo;s progress.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
