<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DevOps, SRE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/devops-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/devops-sre/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to interviews again, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some observations. This time we are talking about DevOps and SRE in enterprise companies and their recruitment processes.&#xA;DevOps/SRE I was unemployed and full of time, so I decided to interview DevOps. In vain that the course on Linux was held on Udemy (a joke, sarcasm, still passed, but to write about it is embarrassing)?! And then I liked the process much more. It consisted of only two steps: general knowledge and troubleshooting.&#xA;In general, the interviewer had a list of questions, but he allowed himself to deviate a little from it, which gave some liveliness to the conversation. We&amp;rsquo;ve had time to discuss Linux loading, networking, container operation, and databases. In general, what happens in the universe one way or another?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps your main problem is not technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</guid>
      <description>Right now, somewhere is suffering the disaster of another project of a wage calculation system&amp;hellip; And probably not alone.&#xA;Why did that happen? Because the developers chose Ruby instead of Java or Python instead of Smalltalk? Because you decided to use Postgres instead of Oracle? or because, although you ought to have selected Linux, you liked the Windows platform better? As you know, all project failures are usually blamed on technology. But was your task really so complex that the Java capabilities were not enough for it?&#xA;Projects are usually created by people, and it is these people that determine the success or failure of the whole project. And once that&amp;rsquo;s the case, we need to think a little bit about how to help them succeed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
