<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recruiting on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/recruiting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recruiting on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/recruiting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DevOps, SRE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/devops-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/devops-sre/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to interviews again, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some observations. This time we are talking about DevOps and SRE in enterprise companies and their recruitment processes.&#xA;DevOps/SRE I was unemployed and full of time, so I decided to interview DevOps. In vain that the course on Linux was held on Udemy (a joke, sarcasm, still passed, but to write about it is embarrassing)?! And then I liked the process much more. It consisted of only two steps: general knowledge and troubleshooting.&#xA;In general, the interviewer had a list of questions, but he allowed himself to deviate a little from it, which gave some liveliness to the conversation. We&amp;rsquo;ve had time to discuss Linux loading, networking, container operation, and databases. In general, what happens in the universe one way or another?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge test</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/knowledge-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/knowledge-test/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to interviews again, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some observations. This time it is about testing knowledge in enterprise companies and how the recruitment process should be constructed.&#xA;Knowledge test So, I talked about five stages of IT interviews. You probably thought I exaggerated. But no: recruiter, Python test, live coding, system design, soft skills. Then another call for the offer presentation. So, the second stage is just some kind of Facebook spam. Not only can it be combined with live coding if it is not just to code but to discuss the solution, but also the questions on it, softly speaking, are stupid. Primitive and old-fashioned. So, according to the company&amp;rsquo;s logic, you can send soaps there, so you don&amp;rsquo;t waste your gentlemen&amp;rsquo;s time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/system-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/system-design/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to interviews again, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some observations. This time we talk about system design enterprise companies and how the recruitment process should be constructed.&#xA;System Design In senior grades, another type of interview appears—system design. In one hour you have to design systems, thinking about the architecture of which in a real project you would spend several weeks. IDEF0, UseCase, ER, C4, DFD, BPMN—forget these scary words; there&amp;rsquo;s no time for them. Figac-figac and Proudakshen. Requirements collection -&amp;gt; usage options -&amp;gt; system requirements -&amp;gt; processing -&amp;gt; presentation of the solution, time has passed. The main thing here is more basic words: to build a smart face and somewhere to put kafka. Then they&amp;rsquo;ll be behind you in 40 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-tips/</guid>
      <description>The fate of fate I started to go to interviews again, and I want to share some observations. On this, I just give advice to everyone in enterprise companies about how the recruitment process should be structured.&#xA;Advice to candidates In the last five years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been through several hundred interviews on both sides. So, some life hacking:&#xA;You&amp;rsquo;re going to have to go through the windshields. Those you&amp;rsquo;re not going to go to. You pump the skill, or suddenly something interesting turns out to be, or it&amp;rsquo;ll be the only place with the offer. You never know what&amp;rsquo;s in a box of candy.&#xA;Get some sleep and let yourself rest on the day of wrath. The same live coding is quite a dumb thing; the solution may not come during the call but will appear immediately after.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/screening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/screening/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to interviews again, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some observations. This time we talk about Screening in enterprise companies, and how the recruitment process should be constructed.&#xA;Screening It all starts with it, and tech-screening becomes the norm. Recruiter directly on the first call asks cavernous questions and checks with sparkling. For example:&#xA;how to stop the container? unchanged data typesx in python? What&amp;rsquo;s the PID of the Linux kernel? how do you decipher CAP and PACELC? &amp;hellip; Some of them go even further and create an entire platform with small pieces of code that can be run. 20 questions in 20 minutes. &amp;ldquo;How do I send a message to the generator?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;What does this code do?&amp;rdquo; Well, he knows, I&amp;rsquo;t just miss that code on a review, because it&amp;rsquo;s wild.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live Coding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/live-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/live-coding/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to interviews again, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some observations. This time we talk about live coding in enterprise companies and how the recruitment process should be constructed.&#xA;Live Coding There&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of noise around him. Some people like it (interviews), some people don&amp;rsquo;t like it at all (candidates), and someone goes to a psychologist after him for six months. This is not really to understand that the candidate is able to code; there are not enough extensive projects on Github, profile articles with code, reports after all. As I was told, this is done to ensure that everyone is treated equally in recruitment. Well, good luck hiring a leader or a gentleman in five rounds. At the second, he&amp;rsquo;ll ask himself, &amp;ldquo;Do I really need this?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
