<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Everything is run by business</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-is-run-by-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-is-run-by-business/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to developing corporate software applications, the architect should act as a kind of go-between for the technical and business communities inside the organization, representing and defending each group&amp;rsquo;s interests, resolving conflicts on a regular basis, and allowing the business to operate as usual. The architect&amp;rsquo;s technology choices must take the organization&amp;rsquo;s business objectives and external surroundings into consideration.&#xA;Before beginning a software development project, a software development business usually plans and promotes the desired return on investment (ROI). The architect has to acknowledge this signal and the resulting limitations on the product&amp;rsquo;s business value.This will help prevent the need of technical solutions that could be extremely expensive. The return rate should be taken into consideration in the overall target context when talking about the technical architecture and implementation with the development team and when interacting with management (during the process of determining how to strike a balance between the cost and benefit of a given function).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
