<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Investigate the topic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/investigate-the-topic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/investigate-the-topic/</guid>
      <description>A proficient software architect possesses expertise not only in technology but also in the domain of the problem that needs to be resolved. In the absence of this information, it is challenging to comprehend the business side of the assignment, goal, and specifications of the organization; consequently, it is challenging to create an efficient architecture that satisfies the demands of the business.&#xA;Understanding the business&amp;rsquo;s problems, goals, and needs in order to translate them into a technical architectural solution that satisfies them is the responsibility of the software architect. Understanding the issue helps the architect choose which patterns to use, how to schedule expansions in the future, and how to consider market trends to better prepare for change. For instance, workflow-based design works well in certain contexts (such as the insurance industry) and service-oriented architecture in others (such as the financial markets).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything is run by business</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-is-run-by-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/everything-is-run-by-business/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to developing corporate software applications, the architect should act as a kind of go-between for the technical and business communities inside the organization, representing and defending each group&amp;rsquo;s interests, resolving conflicts on a regular basis, and allowing the business to operate as usual. The architect&amp;rsquo;s technology choices must take the organization&amp;rsquo;s business objectives and external surroundings into consideration.&#xA;Before beginning a software development project, a software development business usually plans and promotes the desired return on investment (ROI). The architect has to acknowledge this signal and the resulting limitations on the product&amp;rsquo;s business value.This will help prevent the need of technical solutions that could be extremely expensive. The return rate should be taken into consideration in the overall target context when talking about the technical architecture and implementation with the development team and when interacting with management (during the process of determining how to strike a balance between the cost and benefit of a given function).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
