<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating in the Dark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>The software components of the system are interrelated. Architecture refers to the hierarchical structure of various program components as well as their cohesive connections.Individual program components and servers are frequently simplified into rectangles connected by arrow keys on diagrams showing such systems.&#xA;The meaning of a single little arrow could be &amp;ldquo;Synchronous SOAP-XML Request/Respond via HTTP.&amp;rdquo; One chart element cannot include all the information that is available. Since there is typically not enough room for everything to be written, we label the arrow with &amp;ldquo;Search by product code&amp;rdquo; (for external users) or &amp;ldquo;XML through HTTP&amp;rdquo; (from the perspective of internal implementation).&#xA;Although it appears to be a direct communication, the arrow connecting the programs is not. Hardware and software components occupy the space in between rectangles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failures are unavoidable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/failures-are-unavoidable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/failures-are-unavoidable/</guid>
      <description>It increases the likelihood that the system will experience a malfunction at least once in any given period of time, but it also makes it possible to survive isolated hardware failures.&#xA;The software code is also vulnerable. We employ monitoring tools to keep track of application issues, but because they depend on software, these tools might sometimes break.&#xA;We try to automate our diagnoses, actions, and workflows since humans are fallible. Automation increases the likelihood of errors coming from rule noncompliance but decreases the likelihood of errors resulting from rule violations. More circumstances can be handled by a human than by any automated technology.&#xA;For this reason, we&amp;rsquo;re including monitoring techniques in automated solutions. new software with fresh bugs. Networks are made up of hardware, software, and long communication lines.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
