<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organization on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organization on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating architecture as the art of balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-architecture-as-the-art-of-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-architecture-as-the-art-of-balance/</guid>
      <description>The traditional technical processes that come to mind when creating a software architecture are breaking the system down into its component parts, defining interfaces, assigning tasks, using templates, and performance tuning. The architect also needs to consider a variety of additional factors, such as output management, deployment settings, simplicity of usage, safety, and ease of maintenance.All of these procedural and technical details, meanwhile, have to be pertinent to the needs of the stakeholders.One of the best ways to make sure that the requirements specifications for the product being developed are comprehensive is to consider these interests during the requirements analysis process.&#xA;Each project participant has interests that impact the corporation as a whole as well as the software development process the company uses. The architect&amp;rsquo;s final set of priorities is derived from a consideration of these interests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There may be several solutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-may-be-several-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-may-be-several-solutions/</guid>
      <description>A single data model, communication format, transport mechanism, and typically a single fundamental architectural element, policy, principle, etc., cannot adequately address every facet of a corporate organization. It appears that the system developers are perpetually surprised and saddened by this fact. It makes sense, though, that the organization—which is denoted here by the thick red line—must be too big and diverse to manage a single table, given that it is large enough to worry about the impact of multiple tables of accounts on the system over the course of the next ten years.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s also quite practical for us. Nonetheless, the contentious, complex, unofficial, and unsettling actual world of business is involved.Even worse, you have to deal with people&amp;rsquo;s perceptions of particular situations in specific regions of the world rather than the actual world.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
