<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interview at Enterprise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-at-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-at-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started attending interviews once more, and I would want to offer some findings. This episode, we discuss screening in large corporations and the design of the hiring process.&#xA;Screening From there, tech-screening spreads like wildfire. On the initial call, the recruiter asks a ton of questions and checks with sparkling. As an illustration:&#xA;How can the container be stopped? Python&amp;rsquo;s unaltered data typesx? What is the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s PID? How are CAP and PACELC interpreted? -&amp;hellip; Some even go so far as to build a full platform out of executable little bits of code. Twenty minutes, twenty questions. &amp;ldquo;How do I send a message to the generator?&amp;rdquo; Alternatively &amp;ldquo;What does this code do?&amp;rdquo; He&amp;rsquo;s aware that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t just overlook that code on a review because it&amp;rsquo;s so bizarre.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps your main problem is not technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</guid>
      <description>Somewhere right now, a different wage calculation project is failing miserably&amp;hellip; and most likely not by yourself.&#xA;What caused that to occur? because the developers opted for Ruby over Smalltalk or Java or Python? since you choose to utilize Postgres over Oracle? or because you preferred the Windows platform even if you should have chosen Linux? As you are aware, technology is frequently held responsible for project failures.&#xA;People normally establish projects, and it is up to these individuals to decide whether the project as a whole succeeds or fails. And once that is the case, we ought to consider our options for assisting them in being successful.&#xA;Per, you believe that there is a team member that is underperforming and impeding the project&amp;rsquo;s progress.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
