<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canada on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canada on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/install-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/install-me/</guid>
      <description>I am not at all interested in your program.&#xA;I have plenty of my own problems and a long list of tasks. I only visited your site because of unverified rumors that your program would solve all my problems. Please forgive my skepticism.&#xA;If eye-tracking studies are correct, I&amp;rsquo;ve already read the headline and am scrolling through the page looking for the blue underlined link Download Now. By the way, if I accessed this page from a browser running on Linux and my IP is from Canada, it can be assumed that I need the Linux version from a North American mirror, so please don&amp;rsquo;t ask about that. I understand that the file download dialog will open immediately, so I&amp;rsquo;ll send this thing to my downloads folder and continue reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incredible, but testers are your friends</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/incredible-but-testers-are-your-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/incredible-but-testers-are-your-friends/</guid>
      <description>They may call themselves quality control or quality assurance, but many programmers simply call them a nuisance. My experience shows that programmers often have a hostile relationship with those who test their programs. &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re too picky&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;They want everything to be perfect&amp;rdquo; are common complaints. Sound familiar?&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but I have always had a different view on the work of testers. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because the &amp;ldquo;tester&amp;rdquo; at my first job in Canada was the firm&amp;rsquo;s secretary. A very pleasant lady who handled paperwork and tried to teach a couple of young programmers professional behavior in the presence of clients. She also had the gift of spotting any program defect, even the most inconspicuous, in a matter of seconds.&#xA;At that time, I was working on a program written by an accountant who considered herself a programmer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
