<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Business runs everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/business-runs-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/business-runs-everything/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the creation of corporate software applications, the architect should serve as a sort of intermediary within the organization between the technical and business communities, representing and defending the interests of each while frequently mediating disputes and letting the business run its operations. The commercial goals of the organization and its external environment must inform the architect&amp;rsquo;s technological decisions.&#xA;A software development company typically plans and advertises the intended return on investment (ROI) prior to starting a software development project. This signal must be accepted by the architect, along with the ensuing restrictions on the product&amp;rsquo;s value for the business.This will assist in avoiding technological solutions that can result in exorbitant costs. When discussing the technical architecture and implementation with the development team, as well as when interacting with management (in the process of figuring out how to strike a balance between the cost and benefit of a given function), the return rate ought to play a significant role in the overall target context.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
