<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating architecture as the art of balance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-architecture-as-the-art-of-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-architecture-as-the-art-of-balance/</guid>
      <description>The traditional technical processes that come to mind when creating a software architecture are breaking the system down into its component parts, defining interfaces, assigning tasks, using templates, and performance tuning. The architect also needs to consider a variety of additional factors, such as output management, deployment settings, simplicity of usage, safety, and ease of maintenance.All of these procedural and technical details, meanwhile, have to be pertinent to the needs of the stakeholders.One of the best ways to make sure that the requirements specifications for the product being developed are comprehensive is to consider these interests during the requirements analysis process.&#xA;Each project participant has interests that impact the corporation as a whole as well as the software development process the company uses. The architect&amp;rsquo;s final set of priorities is derived from a consideration of these interests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failures are inevitable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/failures-are-inevitable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/failures-are-inevitable/</guid>
      <description>It makes it possible to withstand isolated hardware failures, but it also makes it more likely that the system will malfunction at least once at any given time.&#xA;Additionally susceptible is the software code. We use monitoring tools to record application problems; but, as these tools rely on software code, they are likewise susceptible to malfunction.&#xA;Because humans make mistakes, we attempt to automate our workflows, diagnoses, and actions.Automation lowers the probability of errors resulting from rule violations but raises the probability of errors originating from rule noncompliance.A human being can react to a wider variety of situations than any automated technology.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;re including monitoring methods in automation tools because of this. Fresh flaws in new software. Hardware, software, and lengthy communication links make up networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architectural compromises</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/architectural-compromises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/architectural-compromises/</guid>
      <description>High performance, high availability, high security, and high abstraction cannot all be achieved at the same time in an architecture. Software architects just need to be aware of, comprehend, and share one true story with their clients and peers. I&amp;rsquo;m referring to Vaza&amp;rsquo;s past.&#xA;There was a conflict between Sweden and Poland in 1620. The Swedish King ordered the building of a gallion known as the Vase in an attempt to swiftly conclude this costly conflict. The ship was unique. It had different specifications than any other ship of the era. In addition to carrying 64 weapons on two battery decks and transporting 300 men at a time safely to Poland by sea, it had to be longer than sixty meters. There was not enough money, and there was running out of time (sounds familiar?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication is the king, clarity and leadership are his true companions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-the-king-clarity-and-leadership-are-his-true-companions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-the-king-clarity-and-leadership-are-his-true-companions/</guid>
      <description>All too frequently, software architects reside in ivory towers, dictating technologies and instructions to developers while leaving them with little to no guidance. Simultaneously, this causes conflict, which is soon followed by a &amp;ldquo;popular uprising.&amp;rdquo; The end product is a piece of software that bears no relation to the original specifications. It is imperative for any software architect to be able to articulate to his peers the aims and purposes of the software project. Effective communication relies on leadership and clarity.&#xA;A communication procedure that is clear and concise. A one hundred-page document explaining your architectural choices will not be read by anyone in your group. Effective communication of ideas is essential for any program or effort to succeed. When starting work on the project, stick to brief explanations and don&amp;rsquo;t start writing lengthy word descriptions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity is better than versatility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/simplicity-is-better-than-versatility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/simplicity-is-better-than-versatility/</guid>
      <description>The fact that many frameworks, class libraries, basic services, and other infrastructure code are made to be used universally and aren&amp;rsquo;t tied to any particular application is a common issue with them. The majority of developers specialize in particular systems; therefore, trying to be as versatile as possible is rarely beneficial to them. The greatest approach to reaching universality is not by universality based on supposition but rather by a thorough comprehension of known concrete cases and a study of their essence to uncover a fundamental common solution. Simplicity is the outcome of practical experience.&#xA;Simplifying an architectural design over adding more features makes it easier to choose between two options that are equivalent in every other way. Choose a more straightforward and needs-based solution over a more complex and adaptable one when there are two options.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business runs everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/business-runs-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/business-runs-everything/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the creation of corporate software applications, the architect should serve as a sort of intermediary within the organization between the technical and business communities, representing and defending the interests of each while frequently mediating disputes and letting the business run its operations. The commercial goals of the organization and its external environment must inform the architect&amp;rsquo;s technological decisions.&#xA;A software development company typically plans and advertises the intended return on investment (ROI) prior to starting a software development project. This signal must be accepted by the architect, along with the ensuing restrictions on the product&amp;rsquo;s value for the business.This will assist in avoiding technological solutions that can result in exorbitant costs. When discussing the technical architecture and implementation with the development team, as well as when interacting with management (in the process of figuring out how to strike a balance between the cost and benefit of a given function), the return rate ought to play a significant role in the overall target context.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
