<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Components on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/components/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Components on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating in the Dark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/creating-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>The software components of the system are interrelated. Architecture refers to the hierarchical structure of various program components as well as their cohesive connections.Individual program components and servers are frequently simplified into rectangles connected by arrow keys on diagrams showing such systems.&#xA;The meaning of a single little arrow could be &amp;ldquo;Synchronous SOAP-XML Request/Respond via HTTP.&amp;rdquo; One chart element cannot include all the information that is available. Since there is typically not enough room for everything to be written, we label the arrow with &amp;ldquo;Search by product code&amp;rdquo; (for external users) or &amp;ldquo;XML through HTTP&amp;rdquo; (from the perspective of internal implementation).&#xA;Although it appears to be a direct communication, the arrow connecting the programs is not. Hardware and software components occupy the space in between rectangles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There could be a number of answers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-could-be-a-number-of-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-could-be-a-number-of-answers/</guid>
      <description>Every aspect of a business organization is too complex for a single data model, communication format, transport mechanism, and usually a single core architectural element, policy, principle, etc. to handle well. It seems that this truth always surprises and depresses the system developers. But given that the company is large enough to be concerned about the effects of numerous tables of accounts on the system over the next ten years, it makes sense that it must be too huge and diverse to manage a single table. The organization is represented by the thick red line in this example.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s also quite useful to us. Still, it involves the tense, intricate, informal, and disconcerting real world of business. Even worse, instead of dealing with real reality, you have to deal with people&amp;rsquo;s views of specific situations in specific parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towers are not scalable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/towers-are-not-scalable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/towers-are-not-scalable/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s common to compare software development to constructing highways, dams, and skyscrapers. This analogy makes sense in a few key areas.&#xA;The intricacy of the construction process is more challenging than designing a structure that will remain in its final location when it is built.This technique will result in a ready-made building at the end from an empty site at the start. Every employee should be able to use their professional abilities throughout this time, and the partially constructed structure should hold together. This comparison has practical implications for large-scale integrated system implementation. (And almost all web and business apps fall under the &amp;ldquo;integrated&amp;rdquo; category!) The classic &amp;ldquo;Big Bang&amp;rdquo; deployment involves bringing a large number of beams into the desert, launching them into the air, and then waiting for the beams to self-assemble into a building.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
