<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/information/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/information/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Try before you decide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/try-before-you-decide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/try-before-you-decide/</guid>
      <description>Many choices must be taken during the attachment-forming process. Some may be related to the library or infrastructure selection, while others may be related to the application of particular design patterns.In any event, the architect is often in charge of making the choice. The architect gathers all available data, considers it for a period, and then specifies the guidelines that the developers must follow. The fact that there is an improved method won&amp;rsquo;t surprise you.&#xA;The decision-making process is described by Mary and Tom Poppendieck in their work on lean development. They think that the ultimate choice should wait until the most crucial moment, when the team&amp;rsquo;s inaction will have permanent (or difficult to reverse) repercussions and a decision will be made on its behalf if no decision is made.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use the bug tracking system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-use-the-bug-tracking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-use-the-bug-tracking-system/</guid>
      <description>No matter what you call them – bugs, defects, or even design side effects – it is impossible to eliminate them completely. For a project to be successful moving forward, it is very important to be able to correctly write an error report, as well as to know what to pay attention to in it.&#xA;In a good bug report, three things should be described: • How to reproduce the error – as accurately as possible – and how often the error manifests itself. • What was supposed to happen – how do you see it? • What is actually happening – at least the data you were able to record.&#xA;The volume and quality of the provided information equally characterize the report&amp;rsquo;s author, as well as the error itself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
