<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architect on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/architect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architect on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/architect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-up/</guid>
      <description>Many of us started our careers as architects in some form of very technical role where computer communication skills were essential to succeed.However, our primary means of communication as architects is with other people. Your ability to communicate effectively is essential for success, whether you are arguing with developers about the benefits of using a template or outlining the advantages and disadvantages of purchasing intermediary software to management.&#xA;It is challenging to measure the architect&amp;rsquo;s influence on the project objectively, but one thing is certain: the &amp;ldquo;correctness&amp;rdquo; of the architect&amp;rsquo;s actions will not have an impact on the trajectory of his career if the developers consistently disregard his instructions and the management does not value his advice. Skilled architects know that they must &amp;ldquo;promote&amp;rdquo; their concepts, and good communication is necessary for this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The architect must be a practitioner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-architect-must-be-a-practitioner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-architect-must-be-a-practitioner/</guid>
      <description>A competent architect ought to lead by example. He should be able to take the position of any team member and handle any task, including creating modular tests, conducting performance tests, and setting up networking and the assembly process. In the absence of a thorough comprehension of all available technologies, an architect is really no different from a regular project manager.Although it is rather typical for team members to be more knowledgeable in their specialized professions, they are unlikely to be able to trust their architect unless he is conversant with the technology being employed.Since an architect serves as a liaison between the technical team and the company, as has already been mentioned, he must be well-versed in all technical facets in order to represent the team to the business management without continuously seeking assistance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There are no solutions for all cases of life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-are-no-solutions-for-all-cases-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-are-no-solutions-for-all-cases-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Since there isn&amp;rsquo;t a single, all-encompassing solution for a broad variety of various challenges, the architect must constantly hone and enhance his &amp;ldquo;context noe poche.&amp;rdquo; In &amp;ldquo;Systems Architecting: Creating &amp;amp; Building Complex Systems&amp;rdquo; (Prentice Hall, 1991), Eberhardt Rechtin writes:&#xA;Most likely, he would say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just using common sense.&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;&amp;hellip;&amp;gt; It might be preferable to use the phrase &amp;ldquo;context sensation&amp;quot;1—knowledge of what is relevant in a certain context—instead of the word &amp;ldquo;sensual.&amp;rdquo; Through education, experience, and case studies, the architect-practitioner can develop a strong contextual awareness by the time they are asked to tackle a system-level issue, which typically takes decades.&#xA;I believe that one of the main issues facing the software business is that projects are frequently assigned to individuals who lack sufficient contextual awareness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business runs everything</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/business-runs-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/business-runs-everything/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the creation of corporate software applications, the architect should serve as a sort of intermediary within the organization between the technical and business communities, representing and defending the interests of each while frequently mediating disputes and letting the business run its operations. The commercial goals of the organization and its external environment must inform the architect&amp;rsquo;s technological decisions.&#xA;A software development company typically plans and advertises the intended return on investment (ROI) prior to starting a software development project. This signal must be accepted by the architect, along with the ensuing restrictions on the product&amp;rsquo;s value for the business.This will assist in avoiding technological solutions that can result in exorbitant costs. When discussing the technical architecture and implementation with the development team, as well as when interacting with management (in the process of figuring out how to strike a balance between the cost and benefit of a given function), the return rate ought to play a significant role in the overall target context.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
