<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Users on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/users/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Users on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/users/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interfaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/interfaces/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common tasks in software development is interface specification. Interfaces exist at the highest level of abstraction (user interfaces), at the lowest level (function interfaces), and at intermediate levels (class interfaces, libraries, etc.). Regardless of what you are doing—aligning with end users on their future interaction with the system, collaborating with developers to develop the API specification, or declaring private class functions—interface design is an important part of your job. If you handle it well, using your interfaces will be a pure pleasure, and user productivity will increase. If you handle the task poorly, your interfaces will become a source of frustration and errors.&#xA;Good interfaces possess the following properties:&#xA;They are easy to use correctly. Users of a well-designed interface almost always use it correctly because that is the path of least resistance for that interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two mistakes can cancel each other out, making them difficult to correct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/two-mistakes-can-cancel-each-other-out-making-them-difficult-to-correct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/two-mistakes-can-cancel-each-other-out-making-them-difficult-to-correct/</guid>
      <description>Code never lies, but it can be internally contradictory. Sometimes contradictions cause confusion: how can this even work?&#xA;In his interview, Allan Klumpp, the lead software developer for the Apollo lunar module, revealed that the engine control software contained a defect that caused the lunar module to behave erratically. However, there was another bug in the program that compensated for the first one, and during the Apollo 11 and 12 moon landings, this software was successfully used before the bugs were discovered and fixed.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a function that returns an exit code. Let&amp;rsquo;s say it returns false when it should return true. Now imagine that the calling function does not implement the check for the return value. Everything works perfectly until one day someone discovers the lack of a check and adds it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use quantitative criteria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/use-quantitative-criteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/use-quantitative-criteria/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Fast&amp;rdquo; cannot be a requirement. Nor can &amp;ldquo;having a good response time.&amp;rdquo; Or, let&amp;rsquo;s say, &amp;ldquo;scalable.&amp;rdquo; The main reason is the lack of objective criteria for meeting such requirements. But users still need these characteristics. The architect&amp;rsquo;s task is to ensure that the system possesses the necessary qualities and to balance the inevitable contradictions that arise. between them. Without objective criteria, the architect depends on whims the client (&amp;ldquo;No, I can&amp;rsquo;t accept the program – it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work fast enough&amp;rdquo;) and the developers, obsessed with their compulsions (&amp;ldquo;No, the program isn&amp;rsquo;t ready yet – it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work fast enough&amp;rdquo;).&#xA;Usually, we try to record all such requests, just like any other requirements. But this record often looks like a set of vague epithets: &amp;ldquo;flexible,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;easy to accompany,&amp;rdquo; and so on.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
