<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Success on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Success on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No &#34;I am in architecture&#34; exists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-is-no-i-am-in-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-is-no-i-am-in-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Of course, there is an &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; in architecture. However, this is not the primary &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; that draws attention and controls conversations. It only takes a series of letters. For us software architects, what does that mean? Sometimes, our greatest threat comes from our own ego. Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen architects who: • believe they know the specifications better than the clients; • see developers as resources employed to carry out their concepts; or • dismiss any skepticism regarding their own or other architects&amp;rsquo; ideas? Any seasoned architect has probably made at least one of these errors at some point.I&amp;rsquo;ve given in to all of them and have gained harsh insight from my mistakes.&#xA;Why is this taking place? • Our success has already been attained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/stand-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/stand-up/</guid>
      <description>Many of us began our careers as architects in highly technical roles requiring proficiency with computer communication. Nonetheless, as architects, interpersonal communication is our main mode of exchange. Whether you are debating the merits of employing a template with developers or summarizing the benefits and drawbacks of buying intermediate software for management, your ability to communicate clearly is critical to your success.&#xA;It is difficult to assess the architect&amp;rsquo;s impact on the project objectively, but one thing is for sure: if the developers routinely disobey his instructions and the management does not value his advice, then the &amp;ldquo;correctness&amp;rdquo; of the architect&amp;rsquo;s actions will not affect the course of his career. Professional architects are aware that they need to &amp;ldquo;promote&amp;rdquo; their ideas, and effective communication is essential to this.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
