<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Defect on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/defect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Defect on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/defect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Professional programmer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/professional-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/professional-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Who can be considered a professional programmer? The most important trait of a professional programmer is personal responsibility. Professional programmers are responsible for their careers, their evaluations, their deadlines, their mistakes, and their expertise. A professional programmer does not shift this responsibility onto others.&#xA;A professional is responsible for their own career. Reading and learning are your responsibilities. Staying up-to-date with the latest industry advancements and technologies is your responsibility. Too often, programmers believe that their education is the employer&amp;rsquo;s job. Sorry, that is completely incorrect. Do you think doctors believe that too? Lawyers? No, they study in their free time and at their own expense. They spend a significant amount of their free time reading journals and court rulings. They maintain their professional level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two mistakes can cancel each other out, making them difficult to correct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/two-mistakes-can-cancel-each-other-out-making-them-difficult-to-correct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/two-mistakes-can-cancel-each-other-out-making-them-difficult-to-correct/</guid>
      <description>Code never lies, but it can be internally contradictory. Sometimes contradictions cause confusion: how can this even work?&#xA;In his interview, Allan Klumpp, the lead software developer for the Apollo lunar module, revealed that the engine control software contained a defect that caused the lunar module to behave erratically. However, there was another bug in the program that compensated for the first one, and during the Apollo 11 and 12 moon landings, this software was successfully used before the bugs were discovered and fixed.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a function that returns an exit code. Let&amp;rsquo;s say it returns false when it should return true. Now imagine that the calling function does not implement the check for the return value. Everything works perfectly until one day someone discovers the lack of a check and adds it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
