<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Need on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/need/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Need on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/need/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The ethical concerns of software architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-ethical-concerns-of-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-ethical-concerns-of-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to civil rights, identity theft, or malware, the ethical nature of software is made clear. But in calves, it also appears in less unusual situations.The lives of thousands, if not millions, of people are impacted by successful initiatives. They may have both beneficial and detrimental effects.&#xA;Whenever I decide how software should behave, I really decide what its users may and cannot do. Furthermore, the verdict is far harsher than the legislation because there is no appeal court where the selection of required fields or the rigid order of transactions may be disputed.&#xA;The scale effect provides another perspective on this issue. Do you recall articles about the newest viruses on the Internet or popular films? You have to have fulfilled the approximations of the number of working hours lost nationwide as a result of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You underestimate how frequently you negotiate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-underestimate-how-frequently-you-negotiate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-underestimate-how-frequently-you-negotiate/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been &amp;ldquo;buried&amp;rdquo; for savings through ingenious technological &amp;ldquo;budget&amp;rdquo; changes.The conversation goes like this:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Is X really necessary?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;X can replace nearly anything that is required for the system, such as additional servers, software licenses, external backups, and power supplies. The question is always asked in a casual tone, as if you are spending your entire allowance on gum and comic books, and older people ought to think about buying new shells to save their money for the future.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; is the right answer to this question. absolutely necessary.&amp;quot; However, almost no one answers, for whatever reason.&#xA;After all, we have technical education, and every technical occupation requires the ability to compromise.It is evident that nobody will need unconventional power sources if several white wheels are installed in the data center and interns are stationed there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issues can extend beyond what they see in the mirror</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/issues-can-extend-beyond-what-they-see-in-the-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/issues-can-extend-beyond-what-they-see-in-the-mirror/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few different programming projects. All of them encountered problems that turned out to be more difficult than the development team had predicted. This typically manifested itself in the following ways: although a minority of team members saw these problems at an early stage, most workers rejected or ignored any warning signs since they were too late to realize how serious they were.&#xA;This happens for a number of reasons:&#xA;-Project-related issues that don&amp;rsquo;t seem vital at first become crucial when it&amp;rsquo;s too late to fix them. The story of the welded frog is obviously a farce, but it well illustrates the mistakes that can be made in a lot of projects.&#xA;-When other team members don&amp;rsquo;t have the same level of skill or experience, some employees frequently encounter resistance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
