<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Need on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/need/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Need on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/need/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You negotiate more often than you think</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-negotiate-more-often-than-you-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-negotiate-more-often-than-you-think/</guid>
      <description>All of us have been &amp;ldquo;buried&amp;rdquo; for savings by &amp;ldquo;budget&amp;rdquo; modifications, which are clever technology solutions.The dialogue proceeds as follows:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Is X really necessary?&amp;rdquo; The sponsor of the project queries.&#xA;Almost anything that is necessary for the system can be swapped out for X, including extra servers, software licenses, external backups, and power sources. The topic is always posed in a colloquial manner, as though you are spending all of your allowance on comic books and chewing gum, and mature individuals should consider investing in new shells, which will hold their future earnings.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; is the appropriate response to this query. utterly essential.&amp;quot; But virtually nobody responds, for whatever reason.&#xA;We have technical schooling, after all, and compromise is the skill of every technical profession.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Problems can be more than their reflection in the mirror</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/problems-can-be-more-than-their-reflection-in-the-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/problems-can-be-more-than-their-reflection-in-the-mirror/</guid>
      <description>I have several programming projects that I have been working on.They all ran into issues that proved to be more problematic than the development team had anticipated.This frequently happened in the following ways: while some team members identified these issues early on, the majority of employees rejected or disregarded any indications because they didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize their significance until it was too late.&#xA;There are several reasons why this occurs:&#xA;Issues that appear unimportant early in the project grow important when it is too late to address them.Although the tale of the welded frog is undoubtedly exaggerated, it well captures what goes wrong in many undertakings.&#xA;Some workers frequently run into opposition when other team members lack comparable expertise or experience.Even highly compensated seasoned consultants recruited expressly to avoid such issues rarely possess the guts, confidence, and perseverance needed to overcome this opposition.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
