<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Application performance determined by architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/application-performance-determined-by-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/application-performance-determined-by-architecture/</guid>
      <description>An application&amp;rsquo;s performance is determined by its architecture. On the surface, this claim seems obvious, but actual experience suggests otherwise. For example, software architects frequently believe that switching to a different software infrastructure manufacturer can alleviate application performance difficulties. This idea may have originated from the hype around test findings; for example, assertions that the product of the top company outperforms that of its nearest competitor by 25% may have contributed to the development of this view. However, if the leading product completes the operation in 3 milliseconds and the competitor product completes it in 4 milliseconds, the reported 25% (one millisection) represents virtually little given the overall low performance, which is caused by architectural inefficiencies.&#xA;In addition to IT managers and performance testing teams, other groups of people advise you to carry out the subtle configuration of the application&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure, like experimenting with memory allocation operations, connectivity pool sizes, flow pool sizes, and so forth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be guided by uncertainty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/be-guided-by-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/be-guided-by-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>When faced with options, people frequently believe that choosing the best course of action is what really counts. This is not true in terms of design, be it software or anything else. When an alternative exists, an analysis of the uncertainty in the system&amp;rsquo;s design is required. To reduce the importance of design decisions, utilize abstraction and breakdown. Alternatively, use uncertainty as a determining factor to identify places where you can postpone going into detail. You could &amp;ldquo;sew&amp;rdquo; whatever option comes to mind mindlessly into the system, which could tie your hands later.The software product will become less flexible as a result, and arbitrary judgments will begin to take center stage.&#xA;One of the best and most useful definitions of architecture was offered by Grady Booch, who stated that &amp;ldquo;all architecture is the product of design, even though not all designs are intended to result in architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is never a bad time to consider productivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-is-never-a-bad-time-to-consider-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-is-never-a-bad-time-to-consider-productivity/</guid>
      <description>The needs of business application users are mostly stated in functional requirements. The non-functional components of the system, such as performance, flexibility, downtime, support needs, etc., are under the architect&amp;rsquo;s control. Concurrently, the system maintenance team may be given full responsibility for the initial testing of non-functional requirements, or the testing may be postponed until a very late stage of the development process.&#xA;This is a mistake that happens far more often than it should. It could have several foundations. Worrying about the program&amp;rsquo;s speed and flexibility while it isn&amp;rsquo;t yet perfectly performing the required role may seem pointless. The tests themselves are rather complex, as are the test settings. Early working versions of the system may not have been subjected to a realistic load because of their low use intensity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architectural compromises</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/architectural-compromises/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/architectural-compromises/</guid>
      <description>An architecture cannot accomplish high security, high availability, high abstraction, and high performance all at once. All that software architects need to do is know, understand, and relate one real narrative to their peers and clients. I am speaking of Vaza&amp;rsquo;s history.&#xA;In 1620, there was a war between Sweden and Poland. An attempt was made to bring this expensive war to an early end by the Swedish King by ordering the construction of a gallion known as the vase. The ship was not like the others. It was unlike any other ship of the time in its features. It had to be longer than sixty meters in order to safely convey 300 men at a time to Poland while also carrying 64 weapons on two battery decks.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
