<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Problem on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/problem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Problem on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/problem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Архитектор должен быть практиком</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/%D0%B0%D1%80%D1%85%D0%B8%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BA%D1%82%D0%BE%D1%80-%D0%B4%D0%BE%D0%BB%D0%B6%D0%B5%D0%BD-%D0%B1%D1%8B%D1%82%D1%8C-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BA%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/%D0%B0%D1%80%D1%85%D0%B8%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BA%D1%82%D0%BE%D1%80-%D0%B4%D0%BE%D0%BB%D0%B6%D0%B5%D0%BD-%D0%B1%D1%8B%D1%82%D1%8C-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BA%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC/</guid>
      <description>A good architect should set an example to others. He should be able to replace any member of his team and do anything from networking and configuring the assembly process to writing modular tests and performing performance tests. Without a good understanding of the entire range of technologies, an architect is little different from an ordinary project manager.Team members may have deeper knowledge in their narrow fields – this is perfectly normal – but they are unlikely to be able to trust their architect unless he is familiar with the technologies used.As has already been said, an architect is an interface between the technical team and the business, which means that he must understand all the technical aspects in order to play the role of the team representative before the business management, without constantly seeking help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find the true meaning of the needs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/find-the-true-meaning-of-the-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/find-the-true-meaning-of-the-needs/</guid>
      <description>Customers and end-users often demand what they think is an effective solution to a problem. A classic example of this is given by Harry Hillaker, the leading designer of the F-16 Falcon. His group had set the goal of designing an aircraft developing M2–2.5 speeds, which was (and probably remains) a very non-trivial task, especially if the accompanying objective was to create a “cheap” light aircraft. Consider that the force required to overcome the air resistance increases by four times the speed of flight, and imagine how this circumstance affects the weight of the aircraft.&#xA;When the design team asked the Air Force customers why they needed the M2–2.5 speed, they replied, &amp;ldquo;That the aircraft could get out of battle if necessary.&amp;rdquo; When the real need became apparent, the designers were able to solve the main problem and present a workable solution: a mobile aircraft with high traction, providing good acceleration and maneuverability instead of high maximum speed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Решений на все случаи жизни не существует</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/%D1%80%D0%B5%D1%88%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B9-%D0%BD%D0%B0-%D0%B2%D1%81%D0%B5-%D1%81%D0%BB%D1%83%D1%87%D0%B0%D0%B8-%D0%B6%D0%B8%D0%B7%D0%BD%D0%B8-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D1%81%D1%83%D1%89%D0%B5%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B2%D1%83%D0%B5%D1%82/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/%D1%80%D0%B5%D1%88%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B9-%D0%BD%D0%B0-%D0%B2%D1%81%D0%B5-%D1%81%D0%BB%D1%83%D1%87%D0%B0%D0%B8-%D0%B6%D0%B8%D0%B7%D0%BD%D0%B8-%D0%BD%D0%B5-%D1%81%D1%83%D1%89%D0%B5%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B2%D1%83%D0%B5%D1%82/</guid>
      <description>The architect must continuously refine and improve his &amp;ldquo;context noe poche&amp;rdquo;, since there is no single universal solution for a wide range of diverse problems.Eberhardt Rechtin, in his book &amp;ldquo;Systems Architecting: Creating &amp;amp; Building Complex Systems&amp;rdquo; (Prentice Hall, 1991):&#xA;“To learn the basic principles of the “eristic approach” to the design of complex systems, ask an experienced architect what he does when faced with a difficult task.His answer would most likely be, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just using common sense.&amp;quot;&amp;lt;&amp;hellip;&amp;gt;Instead of the term “sensual” it would be better to use the expression “context sensation”1 – knowledge of what is ra zoom in a given context.Education, experience and study of examples allow the architect-practitioner to acquire a considerable power of contextual sense by the moment when it is entrusted to solve a system-level problem – usually it takes decades.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
