<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Error on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/error/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Error on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/error/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A verbose journal will deprive you of sleep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-verbose-journal-will-deprive-you-of-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-verbose-journal-will-deprive-you-of-sleep/</guid>
      <description>When I encounter a system that has been in development or operation for a long time, the first sign of real trouble is always a &amp;ldquo;dirty&amp;rdquo; log. You know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about: it&amp;rsquo;s when clicking a link during normal web page usage results in a whole stream of messages being recorded in the system&amp;rsquo;s single log. Too many log entries can be just as useless as having none at all.&#xA;If your systems are similar to mine, then when your work ends, the work of others begins. After the development is completed, the system will be long and successfully serve customers (if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky). How will you learn about problems if the system is in operation, and what will you do about them?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use the bug tracking system</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-use-the-bug-tracking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-use-the-bug-tracking-system/</guid>
      <description>No matter what you call them – bugs, defects, or even design side effects – it is impossible to eliminate them completely. For a project to be successful moving forward, it is very important to be able to correctly write an error report, as well as to know what to pay attention to in it.&#xA;In a good bug report, three things should be described: • How to reproduce the error – as accurately as possible – and how often the error manifests itself. • What was supposed to happen – how do you see it? • What is actually happening – at least the data you were able to record.&#xA;The volume and quality of the provided information equally characterize the report&amp;rsquo;s author, as well as the error itself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
