<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modern on Korolev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/modern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modern on Korolev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/modern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carefully choose your tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/carefully-choose-your-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/carefully-choose-your-tools/</guid>
      <description>Modern applications are extremely rarely created &amp;ldquo;from scratch.&amp;rdquo; They are assembled from already existing building blocks – components, libraries, and frameworks, and there are several compelling reasons for this:&#xA;The volume, complexity, and sophistication of applications are increasing, while the time allocated for their creation is decreasing. It is more beneficial to spend the time and intellect of developers on business logic code rather than application infrastructure code. - Widely used components and frameworks have fewer chances of encountering errors compared to those developed independently. - High-quality tools are available for free on the Internet, which reduces development costs and simplifies the search for interested developers with the necessary experience. - The creation and maintenance of software require a significant amount of human labor, so it can be cheaper to buy ready-made products than to create them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know your IDE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/know-your-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/know-your-ide/</guid>
      <description>In the 1980s, the programming environment, as a rule, did not differ much from an advanced text editor – at best. Today, we take syntax highlighting for granted, but back then it was a luxury not available to everyone. Code formatting tools existed as external tools, the use of which corrected spacing. Debuggers also &amp;ldquo;lived&amp;rdquo; separately as programs for step-by-step code execution, and working with them required knowing a multitude of mysterious key combinations.&#xA;In the 1990s, companies began to realize the profit potential of more convenient and useful development tools. The Integrated Development Environment (IDE) combined previously offered editing features with a compiler, debugger, formatting tools, and other instruments. At that time, menus and mice became popular, which meant that developers no longer needed to memorize complex key combinations to work with their editor.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
