<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do it in a hurry and escape this crime</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/do-it-in-a-hurry-and-escape-this-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/do-it-in-a-hurry-and-escape-this-crime/</guid>
      <description>Evening is drawing near. Even the air in the room seems to be pulsing at a working pace; the command is pleasant regarding the new features planned for the current iteration. But John is waiting for a date, so he&amp;rsquo;s a touch rushed. He still has time to rush off, rewrite his portion of the code, build it, and register it in the source code management system. After a few minutes, the app&amp;rsquo;s assembly is disrupted, and the &amp;ldquo;red light&amp;rdquo; is lit.John acted rashly, assuming that the team would stall because he didn&amp;rsquo;t have time for automated tests.&#xA;The working rhythm has failed; the circumstances have altered. Everyone is now aware that updating the code from the version control system will cause it to malfunction on their local machines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architectural compromises</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/architectural-compromises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/architectural-compromises/</guid>
      <description>High performance, high availability, high security, and high abstraction cannot all be achieved at the same time in an architecture. Software architects just need to be aware of, comprehend, and share one true story with their clients and peers. I&amp;rsquo;m referring to Vaza&amp;rsquo;s past.&#xA;There was a conflict between Sweden and Poland in 1620. The Swedish King ordered the building of a gallion known as the Vase in an attempt to swiftly conclude this costly conflict. The ship was unique. It had different specifications than any other ship of the era. In addition to carrying 64 weapons on two battery decks and transporting 300 men at a time safely to Poland by sea, it had to be longer than sixty meters. There was not enough money, and there was running out of time (sounds familiar?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never prioritize your resume over the needs of the client</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-prioritize-your-resume-over-the-needs-of-the-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/never-prioritize-your-resume-over-the-needs-of-the-client/</guid>
      <description>As technicians, we select specific technologies, tactics, and methods to address issues not because they offer the best solution but rather because we sincerely want to include them in our synopsis. Making such a decision almost never has favorable outcomes.&#xA;Because you have done so successfully for them, your grateful clients who are waiting in line to refer you to others will be the most potent career catalyst. You will get better service from the kind clients than from any newly created paradigm or trendy object in the new language. Even though staying current with emerging ideas and technology is crucial for architects, you should never try to take on more work at the client&amp;rsquo;s expense. As architects, you should never forget that you are responsible for the success of your organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview at Enterprise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-at-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-at-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started attending interviews once more, and I would want to offer some findings. This episode, we discuss screening in large corporations and the design of the hiring process.&#xA;Screening From there, tech-screening spreads like wildfire. On the initial call, the recruiter asks a ton of questions and checks with sparkling. As an illustration:&#xA;How can the container be stopped? Python&amp;rsquo;s unaltered data typesx? What is the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s PID? How are CAP and PACELC interpreted? -&amp;hellip; Some even go so far as to build a full platform out of executable little bits of code. Twenty minutes, twenty questions. &amp;ldquo;How do I send a message to the generator?&amp;rdquo; Alternatively &amp;ldquo;What does this code do?&amp;rdquo; He&amp;rsquo;s aware that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t just overlook that code on a review because it&amp;rsquo;s so bizarre.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use quantitative criteria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/use-quantitative-criteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/use-quantitative-criteria/</guid>
      <description>You can&amp;rsquo;t make &amp;ldquo;fast&amp;rdquo; a prerequisite. In addition to having a fast reaction time.alternatively, &amp;ldquo;expandable.&amp;rdquo; The primary cause is the absence of impartial standards for fulfilling these obligations.Users nevertheless require these features. Ensuring that the system has the required attributes and balancing the inevitable contradictions that occur between them are the tasks of the architect. Without objective standards, the developer&amp;rsquo;s fixation with obsessive concepts (“No, the program is not ready; it isn&amp;rsquo;t working fast enough”) and the architect&amp;rsquo;s whims (“No, I can&amp;rsquo;t accept the program; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work fast enough”) are what the architect counts on.&#xA;Usually, we make an effort to record all such requests along with any additional specifications. However, this entry frequently appears to be a collection of hazy adjectives, such as &amp;ldquo;flexible,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;friendly to accompany,&amp;rdquo; and so forth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One line of working code costs 500 lines of specification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/one-line-of-working-code-costs-500-lines-of-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/one-line-of-working-code-costs-500-lines-of-specification/</guid>
      <description>It is lovely to promethize. In this regard, specifications are crucial since they establish the framework for system construction. It is crucial to consider the architecture as a whole, taking into account the behavior of individual components as well as the interactions between them on a micro and macro scale.&#xA;Regrettably, architects are frequently enthralled with the design process and are drawn to architectural abstractions. But the specs are worthless in and of themselves. A truly functional system is the software project&amp;rsquo;s ultimate goal. This objective should constantly remain in the architect&amp;rsquo;s mind, and they should never forget that design is merely a tool, not the final product. The skyscraper&amp;rsquo;s architect would soon come to regret disobeying the rules of physics in favor of the building&amp;rsquo;s elegance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There may be several solutions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-may-be-several-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/there-may-be-several-solutions/</guid>
      <description>A single data model, communication format, transport mechanism, and typically a single fundamental architectural element, policy, principle, etc., cannot adequately address every facet of a corporate organization. It appears that the system developers are perpetually surprised and saddened by this fact. It makes sense, though, that the organization—which is denoted here by the thick red line—must be too big and diverse to manage a single table, given that it is large enough to worry about the impact of multiple tables of accounts on the system over the course of the next ten years.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s also quite practical for us. Nonetheless, the contentious, complex, unofficial, and unsettling actual world of business is involved.Even worse, you have to deal with people&amp;rsquo;s perceptions of particular situations in specific regions of the world rather than the actual world.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
