<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communication on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps technology is not your primary issue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-technology-is-not-your-primary-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-technology-is-not-your-primary-issue/</guid>
      <description>Another salary calculation project is currently failing horribly somewhere; it&amp;rsquo;s probably not your fault.&#xA;Why did that happen? because Ruby was chosen by the developers instead of Smalltalk, Java, or Python? since you&amp;rsquo;ve decided to use Postgres instead of Oracle? or because, although you ought to have selected Linux, you liked the Windows platform better? As you are aware, project failures are often attributed to technology.&#xA;Projects are typically started by people, and it is up to these people to determine whether the initiative succeeds or fails overall. And once that&amp;rsquo;s the case, we should think about the ways we might help them succeed.&#xA;As a result, you think that one of the team members is performing poorly and preventing the project from moving forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication is the king, clarity and leadership are his true companions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-the-king-clarity-and-leadership-are-his-true-companions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-the-king-clarity-and-leadership-are-his-true-companions/</guid>
      <description>Too often, software architects live in ivory towers, prescribing to developers the technologies and procedures to follow while providing them with little or no assistance. This simultaneously leads to conflict and, shortly after, a &amp;ldquo;popular uprising.&amp;rdquo; The final result is a piece of software that is completely unrelated to the initial requirements. Any software architect must be able to clearly communicate the goals and objectives of the software project to his peers. Leadership and clarity are prerequisites for effective communication.&#xA;a method of communication that is precise and short. Nobody in your group will read a hundred-page booklet outlining your architectural decisions. Every program or endeavor must have effective concept communication in order to be successful. When you first start working on the project, don&amp;rsquo;t start writing long-word descriptions; instead, stick to succinct explanations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/stand-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/stand-up/</guid>
      <description>Many of us began our careers as architects in highly technical roles requiring proficiency with computer communication. Nonetheless, as architects, interpersonal communication is our main mode of exchange. Whether you are debating the merits of employing a template with developers or summarizing the benefits and drawbacks of buying intermediate software for management, your ability to communicate clearly is critical to your success.&#xA;It is difficult to assess the architect&amp;rsquo;s impact on the project objectively, but one thing is for sure: if the developers routinely disobey his instructions and the management does not value his advice, then the &amp;ldquo;correctness&amp;rdquo; of the architect&amp;rsquo;s actions will not affect the course of his career. Professional architects are aware that they need to &amp;ldquo;promote&amp;rdquo; their ideas, and effective communication is essential to this.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
