<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communication on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/get-up/</guid>
      <description>Many of us started our careers as architects in some form of very technical role where computer communication skills were essential to succeed.However, our primary means of communication as architects is with other people. Your ability to communicate effectively is essential for success, whether you are arguing with developers about the benefits of using a template or outlining the advantages and disadvantages of purchasing intermediary software to management.&#xA;It is challenging to measure the architect&amp;rsquo;s influence on the project objectively, but one thing is certain: the &amp;ldquo;correctness&amp;rdquo; of the architect&amp;rsquo;s actions will not have an impact on the trajectory of his career if the developers consistently disregard his instructions and the management does not value his advice. Skilled architects know that they must &amp;ldquo;promote&amp;rdquo; their concepts, and good communication is necessary for this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication is the king, clarity and leadership are his true companions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-the-king-clarity-and-leadership-are-his-true-companions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/communication-is-the-king-clarity-and-leadership-are-his-true-companions/</guid>
      <description>All too frequently, software architects reside in ivory towers, dictating technologies and instructions to developers while leaving them with little to no guidance. Simultaneously, this causes conflict, which is soon followed by a &amp;ldquo;popular uprising.&amp;rdquo; The end product is a piece of software that bears no relation to the original specifications. It is imperative for any software architect to be able to articulate to his peers the aims and purposes of the software project. Effective communication relies on leadership and clarity.&#xA;A communication procedure that is clear and concise. A one hundred-page document explaining your architectural choices will not be read by anyone in your group. Effective communication of ideas is essential for any program or effort to succeed. When starting work on the project, stick to brief explanations and don&amp;rsquo;t start writing lengthy word descriptions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps your main problem is not technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/perhaps-your-main-problem-is-not-technology/</guid>
      <description>Somewhere right now, a different wage calculation project is failing miserably&amp;hellip; and most likely not by yourself.&#xA;What caused that to occur? because the developers opted for Ruby over Smalltalk or Java or Python? since you choose to utilize Postgres over Oracle? or because you preferred the Windows platform even if you should have chosen Linux? As you are aware, technology is frequently held responsible for project failures.&#xA;People normally establish projects, and it is up to these individuals to decide whether the project as a whole succeeds or fails. And once that is the case, we ought to consider our options for assisting them in being successful.&#xA;Per, you believe that there is a team member that is underperforming and impeding the project&amp;rsquo;s progress.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
