<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code on Tiny Dev Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code on Tiny Dev Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do it in a hurry and escape this crime</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/do-it-in-a-hurry-and-escape-this-crime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/do-it-in-a-hurry-and-escape-this-crime/</guid>
      <description>Evening is drawing near. Even the air in the room seems to be pulsing at a working pace; the command is pleasant regarding the new features planned for the current iteration. But John is waiting for a date, so he&amp;rsquo;s a touch rushed. He still has time to rush off, rewrite his portion of the code, build it, and register it in the source code management system. After a few minutes, the app&amp;rsquo;s assembly is disrupted, and the &amp;ldquo;red light&amp;rdquo; is lit.John acted rashly, assuming that the team would stall because he didn&amp;rsquo;t have time for automated tests.&#xA;The working rhythm has failed; the circumstances have altered. Everyone is now aware that updating the code from the version control system will cause it to malfunction on their local machines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview at Enterprise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-at-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/interview-at-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started attending interviews once more, and I would want to offer some findings. This episode, we discuss screening in large corporations and the design of the hiring process.&#xA;Screening From there, tech-screening spreads like wildfire. On the initial call, the recruiter asks a ton of questions and checks with sparkling. As an illustration:&#xA;How can the container be stopped? Python&amp;rsquo;s unaltered data typesx? What is the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s PID? How are CAP and PACELC interpreted? -&amp;hellip; Some even go so far as to build a full platform out of executable little bits of code. Twenty minutes, twenty questions. &amp;ldquo;How do I send a message to the generator?&amp;rdquo; Alternatively &amp;ldquo;What does this code do?&amp;rdquo; He&amp;rsquo;s aware that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t just overlook that code on a review because it&amp;rsquo;s so bizarre.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One line of working code costs 500 lines of specification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/one-line-of-working-code-costs-500-lines-of-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/one-line-of-working-code-costs-500-lines-of-specification/</guid>
      <description>It is lovely to promethize. In this regard, specifications are crucial since they establish the framework for system construction. It is crucial to consider the architecture as a whole, taking into account the behavior of individual components as well as the interactions between them on a micro and macro scale.&#xA;Regrettably, architects are frequently enthralled with the design process and are drawn to architectural abstractions. But the specs are worthless in and of themselves. A truly functional system is the software project&amp;rsquo;s ultimate goal. This objective should constantly remain in the architect&amp;rsquo;s mind, and they should never forget that design is merely a tool, not the final product. The skyscraper&amp;rsquo;s architect would soon come to regret disobeying the rules of physics in favor of the building&amp;rsquo;s elegance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
